foreign
is a production of Frankie Freitas and
the internet Museum of filmography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of Polo talk
for the week of September 27 1998 this
is an open Forum week which means that
the topic will center around lasers and
holography but we won't have a guest
this week and I thought it would be a
nice idea to take a show and look back
to see where holography was at at a
specific period in time so I thought
let's take a look 10 years ago and see
what was happening in the field of
holography back in the fall of 1988 so
that's what we're going to do on this
show but first I have a few
announcements to make if you're a new
whole talk listener I'd like to welcome
you to the show and I hope you come back
each week to hear more news and
information and special guests with
lasers and Holograms and also if you're
a regular listener you'll notice
something new on the whole talk page and
that is a complete menu of shows from
the last season so if you scroll down
the page itself you'll see a brief
description of each one of the shows and
if you find something that interests you
just click on the link in that show page
that will play for you excuse me uh also
download if you'd like to start a
collection of whole talk shows on your
own computer or floppy disks or whatever
or is it disks just download it to
whatever hard drive you have and you can
play it from your own hard drive anytime
you feel like listening to it also back
in the multimedia theater I have a new
video presentation this video was sent
to me a number of years ago by a friend
of mine in New York and also a friend of
who's in the video and his name is
bartis Allen the video is of Patrick
Boyd when he was doing his post portrait
holography at the Royal College of Art
in London and it shows what the models
go through to get ready for the pulse
portrait and the different outfits that
they're wearing and things like that
it's an eight-minute show and if you
have Real Player 5.0 which you should be
to be listening to the show it will also
play video for you so you might want to
stop back in the multimedia theater and
watch that as well
on occasional shows I'll take a show to
answer listeners questions about lasers
and holography and there's two ways that
you can get on the whole talk show
number one is you can call the toll-free
number which is toll-free across the
United States and that number is
1-800-458-3525 you'll also see the
number listed right in the real audio
window as you're listening down at the
third line there or you can send an
email to wholetalk holoworld.com If you
happen to call in I won't use your real
name on the air I will take your
question in your voice and put it into
the show and answer your question or if
you want to just send an email I'll read
your question on the air and answer it
there as well if you have news and
information that we would like to have
included on an upcoming broadcast please
send it along and I'll see that it gets
on the show
okay so let's move on I have a filing
cabinet that is just packed with
information about holography that
actually goes back into the 40s I have
information on patents and Publications
I have all the magazines and newsletters
that were published and I went in there
to see what I could find from 10 years
ago from 1988 and I came up with four
holographics International laser news
the Hologram newsletter which is a
newsletter that I published from 1983 to
I believe
1991 or 93 and holosphere which was a
publication of the Museum of Photography
in New York so I dusted these babies off
and I figured let's page through here
and see what we have inside these
magazines and see what was happening in
the field of Photography 10 years ago
let's start off with holographics
International and just uh if you'll go
along with me here what I'm going to do
is just I did thumb through these
already so I have a pretty good idea
what I'm going to mention so just stick
with me here as I go through Page by
Page this is a publication that was uh
done out of Great Britain England and
the editor publisher with sunny Baines
now on the inside cover there was a
beautiful
embossed hologram of the saxophone
player and it was done with a device
called a holoscope it said simplest
system for professional holography you
record the picture and based the
horoscope is a photographic camera
traveling along a guide Rail and they
this Con company then initialized and
duplicate your stereograms and it was
produced by hologram Industries in
France
which I imagine is sort of the
predecessor to this new Sony camera
which has a camera that travels along
the rail only it has a desktop size a
holographic printer as well that
contains a little laser diode and a film
transport mechanism that actually does
the development and everything it gives
you your finished hologram right there
so this uh this was actually happening
10 years ago one of the stories in here
was true color it's a story called true
color Oxford blue let me just read the
first paragraph here just to fill you in
on what was happening with this I found
this very interesting work done at
Oxford University's department of
engineering science has produced the
truest most lifelike color hologram to
date
the Hologram shown of a mug full of
colored pencils betters the Holograms
which preceded it because of the laser
beam wavelengths used to expose it the
wavelengths chosen by the Oxford
researchers combined to create a larger
number of colors than ever before making
the finished hologram more realistic
than had previously been possible and it
shows two very nice color pictures of
the Hologram itself Holograms called
pencils natural color hologram by Paul
hubel h-u-b-e-l and this is interesting
because I get a lot of emails asking me
are there true color Holograms and yes
you know I wouldn't say they're common
right now but uh there's been quite a
bit of quite a bit of research into full
color holography in the 90s and it's
something to see that it also goes back
into the 80s
and Other Stories that were in here we
have a an event calendar let's take a
look and see what events were happening
back in 1988
28th of July the 30th of November
exhibition of multicolored Holograms by
John Kaufman and that was in Los Angeles
15th of August the 30th of September
1988 exhibition of holograms at the
Space Coast Science Center in Melbourne
Florida
October 14th to February 5th images and
time and space at the Pavilion San Jose
California I bet you that brings some
Memories Back for some people other
items in this issue is integrating pulse
with other holographic work which was
the lab notes section stereography and
the Art of direct viewing which was an
article by David pizzinelli I believe
I hope I pronounced that right David I'm
sorry if I didn't
oh and the center spray was actually a
color spread on the third International
Symposium on display holography Lake
Forest College
uh some of the pictures on here we have
setsuko ishi with Canadian artist Sydney
Dinsmore that's one of the photos
another photo of Australian artist Paula
Dawson
and also a stereo photograph of one of
her laser transmission Holograms which I
guess was on display there
a nice photo of Paula and Doris Villa
resting in the shade during the
Symposium during one of the breaks a
photo of Ed Dietrich and a photo of TJ
outside as well
now we also have what's up here in the
upper left-hand Corner Mike to tell
which I believe this uh
Mike was from the media lab up at MIT
with Dr Benny
his piece entitled Murray's fourth
birthday won the award for the best
artistic work for the Duran art
institute exhibition
at the Symposium 1988 other articles
about the holographic endoscope
Claudette Abrams personal effects it's a
very nice large
format white light transmission
Holograms are in the magazine as well
another article with a very large
headline t-shirt market up for grabs
and that's basically what we had in this
issue and a nice uh six inch by six inch
embossed hologram on the back of this
Magazine from Global images depicting uh
different things under the sea seashells
structure very nice
next up fall 1988 edition of laser news
volume 8 number three cover story
Roberta Booth the magic of light and
shape and form which was written by
Patty pink who was the editor at the
time Inside Story was by Dr Burke Myers
I just got an email from Bert yesterday
and he's going to be a guest on the show
and he was actually researching
holographic development of showing
internal organs at the Veterans
Administration Hospital in New Orleans
Louisiana and he's going to come on show
and talk about some of his research but
before he was involved in holography he
was actually involved in x-ray
photography not a bones and things of
that nature but an artistic type of
X-ray photography where he would take
common things like mushrooms and
different plants and things of that
nature and do x-ray photography of them
with very beautiful work and I believe
his work has been shown in many
Galleries and also many Publications
across the United States and probably
around the world his article on this
issue of later news was from x-ray art
techniques to holography
very nice also an article on post Ruby
laser portraits in Paris
excuse me
interesting oh here in the back we have
some Publications let's see all the
Publications that were available back in
1988 for holography we had crosstalk
from the interference hologram gallery
holographics International which we just
had on here from BCM holographics
holography news which was published in
Washington DC and I think they may be
out of Denver now I'm not quite sure how
is fear by the Museum of philography the
Hologram which was my newsletter laser
and optronix Leonardo real image
newsletter spie proceedings and young
artists using Science and Technology all
different Publications that were dealing
with lasers and Holograms at the time
my newsletter which I started in 1983.
I'm going to cover of that for fall 1988
was on the Wind of Change holography set
sail on a voyage to a new world and I
believe this was uh actually about
holography and holographic principles
making inroads into the collective
consciousness of mass culture and U.S
and abroad it deals with holographic
perception also a holographic memory and
things of that nature inside the
holography Institute had a little
article about holography in Petaluma
California of course we all know the
left Petaluma and actually went to San
Francisco
a lot of little new Snippets here the
book review for fall 1988 was the magic
of holography by Philip Heckman a theme
at the oppress
1995 not a bad price I don't think you'd
find a book like that today for 19.95.
and another interesting thing the story
of holographic music was in this issue
as well and I'm going to have a special
show coming up we're going to have a
chance to listen to some holographic
music now you know it's stereo music you
have separation in the right Channel and
Left Channel and with some of the home
entertainment systems you'll have your
surround sound and things like that this
shade that I'm going to do is going to
be completely on holographic music and
sound and it gives a three-dimensional
field of listening not only left and
right and front and back but also hype I
will have a couple of Sam Snippets that
you'll be able to download and because
all of this is actually encoded right
into the sound itself it will work on
your own computer if you have a pair of
headphones plug your headphones in
you'll be able to sit down and sit back
and listen to a very interesting field
of sound not only left right back and
forth but going up and down as well one
of the selections is of a fireworks
display where you can hear the fireworks
being launched going up into the sky and
exploding up in the sky
I've heard this and it sounds like
they're actually exploding up in the sky
so it's going to be very interesting I'm
waiting for that CD to come in I just
ordered that not too long ago so that
should be here shortly and that show
should be up maybe within the next week
next few weeks so let's look for that in
October
this issue of holosphere fall 1988
Volume 15 number five let's take a look
and see who is working on holosphere 10
years ago this was a publication of the
Museum of holography in New York uh
acting managing editor was Janine W
McKenna
issue editor with Kent Alexander Arts
editor with Sydney Dinsmore business
editor with sashannah Goldberg education
editor was Andrew pepper technology
editor was Ed Wesley and circulation
manager Mary Duffy
and once again we have a few articles
that are in here about the symposium
that was right about the same time and
also a large article about holographic
bifocal contact lenses by Suzanne
saint-ser cyr I hope I pronounced that
right Suzanne and if I didn't it's not
my fault because I've always heard your
name pronounced by Martin zober down in
Rockford Maryland so he's the one that
made me realize that's how you pronounce
your name so
Suzanne sincere well this is a very
large article in here as well
Graham Saxby with his unusual column for
holosphere johnnings from the UK and
also Department of partly baked ideas
there's a blast from the past and always
a pleasure to read those analytical
naming a new Museum of Photography
director Martha tomkill I had the
pleasure of meeting Martha and working
with her a few times and unfortunately
she lost a battle to cancer several
years after she was appointed to this
position at the Museum of Photography
and I was a very sad day for everyone
the first annual awards ceremony for
achievement in holography I'm going to
go down here and I'm going to be very
sorry if I miss anyone this is a lot of
type and very small type so I'm going to
just browse through this quickly and
read as I
scan this at Dr Stephen Benton presented
Rudy Bookout the 1987 award for
achievement and art holography citing
his landscape series it was particularly
fitting that Dr Benton as the inventor
of rainbow or white light transmission
holography burkhout's preferred mode of
expression made the presentation it was
evident from the remarks that Benton and
burkhound not only share Mutual
admiration but also friendship
the next presentation in 1987 award for
Innovation and commercial use of display
holography was made by Dan Schweitzer to
light fantastic and Richard Seymour for
The holography Illustrated fantasy book
The Mirror
mirror and Dr Alan Cohen who spent 10
years trying to convince lens producers
of the viability of his product was
sincerely touched and honored to receive
the award for his invention of
holographic bifocal lenses
very interesting stuff it also goes on
to welcome the new education director of
the Museum of philography as well Susan
Cowles
officially commencing in the fall Susan
Pals has been hired as the new moh
Director of Education Services in light
of the fact that she was hired by
departing director Ian Lancaster Mrs Mrs
Collins I'm sorry has agreed to a
six-month contract enabling a new
director to review and approve an
extension of her employment agreement so
that was that's what was happening at
the Museum of holography and we have a
photo here from the
first annual awards ceremony of our
happy campers
philographers from left to right Rudy
burkhout Steve Weinstock Jody Byrne
Steve Benton and dieters young share a
laugh before the party
pretty nice stuff what's interesting
going back and and taking a look to see
what was happening with holography 10
years ago
through these Publications
I have a news item I'd like to read
before we close out the show
and I will get into that right away
nominations for the 1998 excellence and
holography awards may be submitted to
the international hologram manufacturers
Association the ihma through October 9
1998. winners will be announced at the
Ninth Annual Hollow pack Hollow print
Awards dinner on November 11 1998 in
Rome Italy each year ihma the worldwide
Association of the holography industry
and reconnaissance International
publisher of holography news combined to
recognize the outstanding commercial
uses of holography from the previous
year any organization involved in the
production of the holographic project
May apply for an award and one of the
following categories new hologram
product authentication product most
novel use of holograms and purposed
designed Holograms nomination forms may
be obtained from ihmas Denver Colorado
or London England offices and if you
have a pencil and paper already I will
give you the ways to contact this
organization in just a few minutes
last year's winners included the New
York Times and light vision Confections
for their holographic lollipop which
received best of year used as a premium
to launch the new times color Edition
Campbell Soup and Van Lear metallized
products won most novel use for their
collectible spaghettio labels with
holographic scenes from Johnny Quest
hologram Industries Hollow CIS project
took honors as an excellent new vehicle
identification system used in France and
American Express and opsec were
commended for their use of special
Holograms and in parentheses it has
Excel grams to stop counterfeiting of
Travelers checks the ihma has already
received a number of innovative
submissions and encourages any company
working with Holograms to apply nominees
must sign a statement vouching that they
have complied with the ihma's code of
conduct including respecting the
copyrights of all parties there is no
cost to apply the winning submissions
will be on display at the hollow pack
Hollow print conference at the Cavalieri
Hilton in Rome Italy and will be shown
at several trade shows through 1999.
the ihma is an association of more than
60 of the world's leading hologram
producers working together to advance
the interests of the industry one of its
foremost achievements is the Hologram
image register a hologram registry that
protects security Holograms from being
copied for more information and here you
go here's your information folks email
Recon USA I'll spell that for you it's
r-e-c-o-n-n-us-a at AOL.com or in Europe
to Ian M Lancaster that's i a n m l a n
c a s t e r like Lancaster Pennsylvania
at compuserve.com or visit their website
at www.ihma.org
the website addressed again is
www.ihma.org and that's our news item
for the week
thank you very much folks for tuning in
I hope you enjoy the show and I hope you
tune in each and every week for more
news and information and special guests
in the field of lasers and holography
here on holotalk this is Frankie Freitas
see you next week